Meseret Haddis

meseretfh@gmail.com | (701)319-0608
303 Pacific Ave Jersey City, NJ 07304 | linktr.ee/meziszem
Edit/VFX Reel - vimeo.com/382338722 (pass: diamondwar)
Color Reel - vimeo.com/796472002 (pass: lean4reel)



SUMMARY

Video editor and producer with over 10 years of experience working with a diverse group of clients from MLB & NHL Network, Eileen Fisher and WeWork to tell stories for everyone. Experienced in all facets of production, with an expertise in writing, project management and post VFX/finishing.

KEY SKILLS

Adobe Premiere ProDavinci ResolveAdobe After EffectsBlender 3DAbelton Live 11Insta/YoutubeHTML/CSSJavaScript (React)Git/GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MLB Network, Freelance Associate Producer

03/2022 to Present

- Managed multiple deliverables from commercial in-bumps and game breakdown analysis for broadcast shows NHL Tonight and On the Fly.
- Provided quality control on rough assemblies from Segment Producers and Junior Editors to tighten edits, color grade, mix and master to be broadcast ready.
- Used Adobe Premiere, After Effects and Photoshop to create dynamic animations, text and color grades, like an 80s throwback color grade.

The Muse, Video Editor

09/2016 to 03/2020

- Creating doc testimonials and branded content like a Japanese language testimonial for WeWork in Japan where subtitles, translation services, and client feedback had to be managed.
- Tested and implemented our unused media to add value to our testimonial docs and increase client satisfaction.
- Worked with Project Managers and freelance crews to ensure brand guidelines are followed and that media delivered reflected clients goals.

NYU's Tisch School of the Arts Film Production Center, Area Technician

10/2013 to 09/2019

- Managed daily equipment checkouts that supported the Undergraduate and Graduate level film shoots.
- Taught informational technical seminars to students and staff about using and maintaining equipment that ranges from camera (Arri, Red, Sony and 16mm film), sound (mixers and microphones) to electric (stands and lighting).
- Managed a staff of student Technical Assistants, which involved training them in our checkout system, using and troubleshooting equipment checkouts/check-ins.

EDUCATION

New York University - Tisch School of the Arts (2010)

BFA Dramatic Writing - Majored in Dramatic Writing with an emphasis on TV Writing and Screenwriting.